# **Eric Alcaide**

C/Pisuerga n2, 7o2a, 08028 Barcelona, Spain • ericalcaide1@gmail.com • +34625429886

linkedin.com/in/ericalcaide • github.com/EricAlcaide

## **Skills**

Multi-langauge coding

Python, Bash, Julia, JavaScript, C++, Web

**Scientific Computing** 

Scientific Python, Julia, Bash

**Problem Solving** 

*Initiative, Creativity, Originality* 

Cloud Computing

AWS, Google Cloud

**Fast Prototyping** 

**Public Speaking** 

**Machine & Deep Learning** 

computer vision, sequence analysis, classification, clustering, sentiment, regression, adversarial attacks, search

methods...

**Teamwork** 

adaptability to different organizations and team

structures

# **Projects**

## 2017 – 2019 Open Source Projects

Created several projects and modules for scientific computing which recieved a high degree of community acceptance:

- **2019**: **MiniFold** ☑ **:** Predict protein foldings from raw sequences (AlphaFold imitation).
- 2018: Keras-WRN ☑ : A package of Wide Residual Networks for image recognition in Keras
- 2018: SearchMethods.jl 2: The Julia package for Search Methods algorithms.
- **2017**: **Pysimplechain** ☑ : Python implementation of a blockchain in less than 200 lines of code.

2017 – 2018 Al Research Paper, E-swish: Adjusting Activations to Different Network Depths ☑ PrePrint proposing a new activation function called E-Swish which showed state of the art results in several computer vision benchmarks.

#### 2017 – 2017 Deep Learning – Can Computers learn? ☑

Research project focused on the AI and Deep Learning field, subfields and the state of the art techniques.

• Exploration of usage of Evolutionary Strategies for architecture optimization in Neural Networks.

# **Professional Experience**

#### 2019 – 2020 Machine Learning Instructor, *Private Tutor*

Given personalized advice and taught Masters' students from different backgrounds (from Computational Linguistics to Biomedical Engineering) different topics: generally speaking about Data Science, AI and ML, and specifically about Text Classification, Image processing and Information representation.

Successfully advised how to carry out Masters' Thesis-level projects.

2019 - 2019 Al & ML Mentor, NonProfit Hackathon for Medicine: BitsXlaMarató

Barcelona, Advised and assisted different teams during the development of healthcare and

visualizations of complex information.

Spain scientific solutions with a strong algorithmic component.

Performed genomic analyses, clustering, HPC (high performance computing) and data

Won several prizes.

2018 - 2019 **Developer, Several Hackathons** 

Got awarded projects on 3 out of 4 hackathons during the past two years: an API for Spain, Switzerland,

mobility data, a decentralized publishing platform and an AI system for psychiatric

patients' follow-up. Hackathon names: Som Hackathon, HackUPC2017 and

HealthHackathon Esade.

2017 - 2017 Data Analyst, Nexow Systems

Applied Deep Learning models to market data analysis, characterization and Spain

prediction during the summer internship.

**Education** 

**USA** 

2018 -Medicine, University of Barcelona

Exceptional student with multiple distinctions. present

2016 - 2018 **High School,** Pare Manyanet Les Corts, Barcelona

Graduated with Honours - 99.5%

Participated in the Debates club, got seleted for Physics and Chemistry olympiads, scored top 1% of my region in Cangur (Mathematics contest) and recieved a honorific

mention from a EU translate contest.

2017 - 2017 **Artificial Intelligence,** *Columbia University* 

> Master's Level Course on Artificial Intelligence (edx.org): Applying key concepts of classic AI and Machine Learning to both classic and real problems such as games and

sentiment analysis.

Courses

2020 - 2020**HPC-based Computational Biomedicine,** Barcelona Spercomputing Centre

Impact and Hands-on experience of applied supercomputing to biomedical problems

(molecular simulations, genomic analysis, tissue modelling...)

2017 - 2017 **Deep Learning Specialization,** Coursera

Learned about the foundations of DeepLearning, how to structure projects, computer

vision, and sequential data.

Languages

**Spanish English** C2 level

Native

German Catalan

Native *A2*